In this video, we'll explore how to
advocate for and create continuous
improvements in a project by
learning about process improvements.
Continuous improvement is an ongoing
effort to improve products or services.
It helps ensure that a product steadily
makes its way toward the best possible
outcome.
Continuous improvement begins with
recognizing when processes and
tasks need to be created,
eliminated, or improved.
Then a project manager must plan for and
implement changes to keep the project on
track. That's where process
improvement comes from.
Process improvement is the practice
of identifying, analyzing,
and improving existing processes to
enhance the performance of your team and
to develop best practices
or to optimize consumer experiences.
When working with your
process improvements,
using a controlled environment
in an experiment can
help you understand if the changes
you're considering fix your problem.
A control is an experiment or
observation designed to minimize
the effects of variables.
Control groups are representative
samples that help you to determine that
the differences between your
experimental groups and
the norm are due to your changes,
rather than something else.
They eliminate alternative
explanations for your results.
If you aren't familiar with this, that's
okay, because I'll break it down for you.
For example, you observe a problem with
your process and put forward a hypothesis,
which is an educated guess about what's
causing the problem and how you'd fix it.
Then you change one
variable in the system,
keeping the control group the same,
and observe your results again.
Let's put this in the context
of Project Plant Pal scenario.
Business is booming for
Office Green, and demand for
your team's new Plant Pal
service is rapidly growing.
To meet the demand, suppliers have
streamlined their process of packing boxes
and putting all plants into
a one-size-fits-all box.
Let's say you're using just one box
size to ship all of your plants.
For smaller plants, there's more padding
added to the box to fill the extra space,
and the plants usually arrive intact.
But larger plants have to be squeezed into
the boxes and sometimes arrive damaged,
according to customer surveys.
To fix this problem, you hypothesize
a potential solution by posing a question.
Would more of the large plants have
arrived intact if they were shipped in
bigger boxes using the same padding
we use for the small plants?
Here is where your control comes in.
You continue to ship half of the larger
plants in the original boxes.
This is your control group.
And you experiment by shipping
the other half in bigger boxes.
Nothing else is different about
the boxes except the size.
The shape, thickness,
box supplier, delivery
addresses—absolutely
everything else
stays exactly the same.
After the larger plants are delivered,
you conduct a new survey.
If more larger plants arrived intact,
your hypothesis is confirmed.
If the results are the same as
they were before the experiment,
you'll need to try something else to
solve the problem of your damaged plants.
Working in a controlled environment
isn't the only way to ensure continuous
improvements.
There are various data-driven improvement
frameworks, like DMAIC and PDCA.
I'll define those and present them in the
context of Plant Pals in the next video.
See you there.